10/24/22, 9:33 PM Adrian Fusco · CV



Adrian Fusco

SOFTWARE ENGINEER AT RED HAT

CONTACT

✓ adrianfuscoarnejo@gmail.com

Galicia, Spain

MY LINKS

adrianfusco

in adrianfusco

m mnf.red/adrianfusco

Introduction

I started to work in the computer science area four years ago. I did a system administrator professional development (CFGS in Spain) and I changed to the development area where I'm very happy.

I had more than two years working as Backend Developer. I started working mainly with the Perl language and after a big migration of technology and services I used PHP and Python where I had the opportunity of learn a lot and grow up.

One year ago I had a big change, I joined to Red Hat, I think the name can tell everything:). I'm currently working with the Code Reliability Engineering team improving the CI systems (and other areas) of the Openstack infrastructure both upstream and downstream.

My skills



Adaptability to change



Autonomy in learning



Proactivity

Technologies and tools

Languages

Galician

NATIVE/BILINGUAL

Italian

FLUID

Spanish

NATIVE/BILINGUAL

English

FLUID

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE/CAREER



Red Hat

Software Engineer
 Sep 2022 — TODAY (1 month)

 $Working\ in\ both\ Code\ Reliability\ Engineering\ and\ Tempest\ team\ in\ both\ upstream\ and\ downstream\ side.$

• Developing new applications in Go and contributing to existing ones.



Associate Software Engineer

Nov 2021 — Sep 2022 (10 months)

Working mainly with the Code Reliability Engineering Team in a global environment with people from different countries.

- Collaboration in upstream and downstream projects in the same and other teams.
- · Experience with CI systems creating pipelines on Jenkins and workflows in GitHub repositories.
- · Experience with Python development (which is used in a high percentage across the OpenStack community).
- Experience with agile and scrum development methodologies.
- Improvement and troubleshooting using the ELK Stack + Beats + Data manipulation using painless scripting in DSL queries.
- Working on Grafana visualizations + Telegraf + InfluxDB.

TECHNOLOGIES AND TOOLS

Python / Jenkins / Ansible / Git / Bash

Dinahosting S.L

Backend Developer

Jan 2020 — Nov 2021 (1 year and 10 months)

PHP & Perl developer. I also work with Go and Python in few projects.

- Web, user control panel and public and private APIs development. I've worked with Zend 2 and Symfony 4 and 5.
- Implementation of AWStats authentication system.
- SSL External Certificates installation automation on Linux servers from user control panel.
- Services and processes automation.
- Creation of development environments using Docker (docker-compose and Dockerfile). I also work with Docker Swarm.
- Improvements on new backup control system using different technologies like Restic, Ceph, Perl frameworks like Mojolicious.
- I've worked with another technologies like ansible and ELK stack.
- I've worked with Xen and KVM technologies using modules like Libvirt for processes automation.
- · Troubleshooting: Technical issues resolution in our website, panel control, public and private APIs and linux servers.
- Continuous integration with Gitlab CI.
- · Using version control like Git.

TECHNOLOGIES AND TOOLS

Python / PHP / Symfony / Go / MySQL / MongoDB / Linux / Docker / Git / Zend / ELK / Perl / Vagrant / mojolicious / restic / ceph / lxd / troubleshooting



Technical Support

Apr 2019 — Oct 2019 (6 months)

Customer support via e-mail, calls and live chat. Troubleshooting technical server issues in: o Web services (apache, nginx). o HTTP acelerator/reverse proxy (varnish). o Mail services (postfix & dovecot). o Database services (MySQL/MariaDB). o Content Management Systems (Wordpress, Prestashop, Moodle, Joomla, ...). o Firewalls (IPtables)

TECHNOLOGIES AND TOOLS

Nginx / Apache / WordPress / Joomla / Prestashop / Moodle / Varnish / Support / http / customer / via / live / calls / chat / technical / issues / aceleratorreverse / proxy / postfix-mta / dovecot / content / management / mysqlmariadb / system / firewalls



Degrees



Universitat Oberta de Catalunya

Computer Science Engineering
 Sep 2019 — TODAY (3 yrs. and 1 month)

Currently studying second year of degree

IES Xulian Magariños

- System Administration Professional Development (CFGS in Spain)
 Sep 2017 Jun 2019 (1 year and 9 months)
 - Database Management
 - Database Administration.
 - Network & Internet Services
 - Network security & High Availability
 - Operative Systems Administration & Implementation.
 - Markup languages.
 - Information management systems.
 - · Network planning.
 - Network administration.
 - Web services implementation.
 - · Training and career counseling.
 - · Entrepreneurship.

Certificates



Linux Professional Institute Certification Level 2 Exam 201-450

Issued by: Linux Professional Institute Certification Level 2 Exam 201-450 Mar 2022 — TODAY (7 months)



PCAP - Certified Associate in Python Programming

Issued by: PCAP – Certified Associate in Python Programming Jul 2020 — Jul 2020



PCEP - Certified Entry-Level Python Programmer

Issued by: PCEP – Certified Entry-Level Python Programmer Jun 2020 — Jun 2020

HIGHLIGHTS/PUBLICATIONS

Linkedin

Jan 2019

10/24/22, 9:33 PM Adrian Fusco · CV



BUT WAIT...

THERE'S EVEN MORE IN MY PROFILE.

This is a short version of my Profile, but a longer one is available where you can see more interesting and relevant data.

+ Click here or scan the QR code